kiip.me 2019-06-13

# Kiip's Privacy Policy

**Table of Contents**

  1. Who is Kiip?
  2. About the Kiip Privacy Policy
  3. The Information We Collect via the Kiip Ad Platform
  4. How We Use the Information We Collect via the Kiip Ad Platform
  5. How We Share the Information We Collect via the Kiip Ad Platform
  6. The Information We Collect via the Kiip Web Services
  7. How We Use the Information We Collect via the Kiip Web Services
  8. How We Share the Information We Collect via the Kiip Web Services
  9. Kiip Cross Device Practices
  10. Kiip General Privacy Practices
  11. Opting Out of the Kiip Ad Platform
  12. Customer Support

**1\. Who is Kiip?**

Kiip, Inc. ("Kiip," "we," "us," "our") is a mobile and desktop advertising and reward network that presents brand messages to consumers in mobile apps, mobile websites, connected devices, and on desktop and laptop computers.

Publishers of mobile apps and websites integrate Kiip technology in order to generate revenue from Kiip for the advertisements that are shown on their properties.

Revenue generated by brands and other entities that show these advertisements is used by both Publishers and by Kiip for various purposes including:

Publisher:

  1. Improving functionality of the app
  2. Developing future apps Paying employees and contractors
  3. Paying costs associated with doing business such as rent, server costs, and taxes.

Kiip:

  1. Improving targeting technologies so you receive more relevant advertisements, offers, and rewards and our Publishers receive the most revenue possible so they can continue to offer the services they provide.
  2. Improving the advertising experience by innovating on the types of ads we show
  3. Ensuring that data privacy is protected
  4. Paying employees and contractors
  5. Paying costs associated with doing business such as rent, server costs, and taxes.

Below is our full Privacy Policy that explains what data of yours we collect, store, and utilize for various purposes. If you have any questions about our privacy policy, please contact [privacy@kiip.me](mailto:privacy@kiip.me).

**2\. About the Kiip Privacy Policy**

Kiip cares about our users’ privacy and is committed to disclosing our data practices. This Privacy Policy explains how Kiip collects, uses, and shares information from and about you when you:

(i) use mobile applications ("Apps") and/or websites ("Sites") from publishers ("Publishers") that have integrated Kiip technology (Kiip Ad Platform)

(ii) use any Kiip Web Services and/or the Kiip Corporate Website ("Kiip Web Services")

Kiip is strongly committed to protecting the privacy of users. Accordingly, we participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) self-regulatory programs and adhere to the DAA Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising.

Kiip is also a member of the Interactive Advertising Bureau ("IAB") and abides by the IAB Code of Conduct including its "Self Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising." More information about the IAB may be found [here](http://www.iab.net/public_policy/codeofconduct).

If you have any questions, please contact us at [privacy@kiip.me](mailto:privacy@kiip.me).

**3\. The Information We Collect via the Kiip Ad Platform**

When you interact with a mobile application or website that has partnered with Kiip for the purpose of displaying advertisements within the app or site, we may collect a variety of information about your device and the Kiip ads that you view.

**The publisher of the app or website that has partnered with Kiip is responsible for obtaining your consent, if required and as applicable, to enable us to collect information from your device.**

The information we collect may include the following:

  * **Information about your device.** We may collect some or all of the following information about your device: device identifiers, which may include Mobile Android Advertising ID (ADID)*, iOS Advertising ID (IDFA)*, MAC address, International Mobile Equipment Identity (IMEI), or other unique device identifiers; device type (e.g., mobile, tablet); type and version of operating system (e.g., Android, iOS); network provider; IP address; mobile browser (e.g. Safari, Chrome, etc.); the carrier user ID (a number uniquely allocated to you by your network provider); timestamp; signal strength; API key (identifier for application); Publisher App version; manufacturer and device model; language setting; time zone; country; device language; DMA (Advertising Region); zip code; network status type (such as WiFi); list of installed apps (the applications and/or processes which are installed or run on your device while the Partner App is active or inactive); Kiip SDK version used by the Publisher.
  * **Mobile Advertising Identifier (MAID) Definition:** Most modern mobile devices (iOS 6, Android 2.3, and Windows 10 and above) provide mobile advertising identifiers. These are randomly-generated alphanumeric codes that are associated with your device that often come with options to reset the identifier and opt-out of Cross-App Advertising. These identifiers have different names depending on the operating system. For example, they are called Google Advertising ID (GAID) on Android devices whereas on iOS, they are called Identifiers for Advertisers (IDFA). They are included to provide advertisers a method to identify your devices without using a permanent device identifier, like your phone's serial number.
  * **Precise Location Information.** The Publisher may allow us to collect and process information about your mobile device’s GPS location (including the latitude, longitude, velocity, or altitude of your mobile device) and the time the location information was recorded. It is the responsibility of the Publisher to obtain your consent prior to the Publisher enabling collecting of such location data – please refer to the Publisher's privacy policy for more information. 

You can stop the collection of this data at any time by disabling the GPS or other location-tracking functions on your device either generally or for that Partner App, provided your device allows you to do this.

To learn how to turn location services on or off at the app or device level in iOS, visit <https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT203033>.

To learn how to turn location services on or off at the app or device level on Android, visit <https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/3467281?hl=en>.

  * **Cookies and Related Tracking Technologies.** When you use the Kiip Ad Platform, we may place and read cookies or access information on your device to obtain information about the performance of our advertising, to record your preferences, and to serve you with advertising that is relevant to your interests. This information may, where permitted by applicable law, then be combined with other information we hold about you.
  * **Information about ads you view.** We collect some or all of the following information about the ads you view: (i) what the ad is about; (ii) the ad type (e.g., text, image, or video); (iii) where the ad is displayed within the Publisher app or website; and (iv) certain information regarding what you do when interacting with or after viewing the ad (e.g., whether you proceed to purchase the product advertised). If the advertiser who created the ad ("Advertiser") uses one of our advertising solutions that involves the voluntary collection of information from you as part of the ad (for example, an ad that contains an Advertiser questionnaire or asks for your email address), and if we collect your voluntary responses, then your responses may be provided directly to the Advertiser and will be governed by the Advertiser's privacy policy.
  * **Information about you from surveys.** From time to time, we may display survey questions to you. These questions are completely voluntary to answer. If you do choose to answer these questions, we may collect, store, and share your responses and those responses may be tied to any or all of the data noted above including device information, precise location information, and information about the ads you viewed.
  * **Information from our partners.** Our Publishers and other third-party partners may sometimes disclose to us information they have separately collected about you so that we can improve the relevance of the ads we serve on their behalf. They do this in accordance with their own privacy policies and subject to their own applicable legal requirements.

**4\. How We Use the Information We Collect via the Kiip Ad Platform**

We use the information we collect through the Kiip Ad Platform, where and as permitted by applicable law, to:

  * Display interest-based advertising customized to individuals’ inferred interests, preferences and locations, and to analyze the effectiveness of the ads.
    * We use this information to provide filtering options for Publishers to manage ads appearing in their apps and website, and to provide targeting options for Advertisers.
    * For example, we use this information to avoid presenting you with ads that you have already seen, and to help our Advertiser clients to serve ads that are more likely to be of interest to you.
  * Track your interaction with ads and to ensure you receive any rewards or offers you have earned via an ad engagement.
  * Respond to your customer support inquiries and to facilitate accurate resolution of any customer support problems that may arise.
  * Perform analysis and research aimed at improving our services.
  * Display contextual advertising (advertising based upon the context of the App).
  * Manage frequency capping of displayed ads (so you don't see the same ad multiple times), conversion tracking (so you can receive any reward earned by interacting with an ad), reporting, and security and fraud detection.

We keep this collected information as long as it remains necessary to provide the Kiip Services.

**5\. How We Share the Information We Collect via the Kiip Ad Platform**

We share the information that we collect through our advertising platform in the following ways:

  * **Publishers and Advertisers.** We may share the information with our Publishers and Advertisers to aid in their understanding of how end users are using our Publishers apps and websites and engaging with ads.
  * **Service Providers.** We may share your information with the service providers who perform services on our behalf, such as providers of analytics, payment processing, product fulfillment, technical infrastructure, data services, engineering and other technical support, and email and customer support. Under our agreements with our service providers, they can use this information only as needed to perform their services; they cannot use it for their own purposes.
  * **Kiip Affiliates.** We may share your information among Kiip affiliates (for purposes hereof, the term "affiliate" means an entity controlled by, controlling or under common control with Kiip) so that we can better provide advertising that is relevant to you.
  * **Legal Purposes.** We may share your information when we believe in good faith that such sharing is reasonably necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding possible illegal activities or to comply with legal process to the extent permissible by applicable laws. We may also share your information in situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of this Privacy Policy or the Terms of Service; or to respond to the claims of violation of the rights of third parties and/or to protect the rights, property and safety of Kiip, our employees, users, or the public and obtaining your consent is difficult. This may involve the sharing of your information with law enforcement, government agencies, courts, and/or other organizations.
  * **Business Transaction.** We may share your information in connection with any merger, reorganization, a sale of some or all Kiip assets, or a financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company.
  * **Consent.** We may share your information in any circumstances where we have your consent.
  * **Third Parties.** Kiip may share the information we collect or receive regarding you as described in this Policy with our publishers, developers, data partners, measurement companies and advertisers. These partners may use this information to show you relevant ads, measure your ad/site interaction, identify your interest areas, better understand the site and app traffic usage or user behaviour in order to refine and improve their services. Such partners' use of the information we share with them will be governed by their privacy policies.

**6\. The Information We Collect via Kiip Web Services**

"Kiip Web Services" means the Kiip dashboard accounts used by Kiip Publishers to manage their use of Kiip’s products and services ("Kiip Dashboard"), and the Kiip corporate website that provides viewers with general information about Kiip and our products and services (the "Kiip Website").

When you use Kiip Web Services, we collect different types of information from and about you based on which service you are using. Please do not use the Kiip Web Service(s) if you do not agree to the collection and use of your information as detailed below.

  * **Information You Voluntarily Provide In Creation of a Kiip Dashboard Account.** If you use Kiip to create a Publisher Dashboard account, we collect information that you provide voluntarily during your creation and use of your Dashboard Account, which may include your name, the name of your company, your username and password, your email address, postal address, phone number, and payment information, as well as any required financial information such as your tax ID, VAT, or sales tax registration number or any other relevant tax number and credit card information.
  * **Use of Kiip Dashboard Collected Information.** We collect information from you that you voluntarily provide via your Dashboard account or that you allow us to access when you do certain things, such as when you:
    * Register to use the Dashboard
    * Edit your Dashboard profile
    * Contact us for customer support
    * Request certain features (e.g., newsletters, updates, or other products)
    * Submit feedback to us.
  * **Information and technologies we may use include:** Device/Usage Information. When you interact with the Kiip Web Services, we may collect information such as (a) IP addresses, unique device identifiers (e.g. Google Advertising ID (GAID), Android ID, ID for Advertisers (IDFA), ID for Vendors (IDFV), MAC address, International Mobile Equipment Identity (IMEI), or other device IDs), and other information about your device(s), browser types, browser language, operating system, the state or country from which you accessed the services; and (b) information related to the ways in which you interact with the Kiip Web Services, such as: referring and exit pages and URLs, platform type, the number of clicks, internal Kiip subdomain names, landing pages, pages viewed and the order of those pages, the amount of time spent on particular pages, the date and time you used the services, error logs, and other similar information. As described in "Third Party Online Analytics and Tailored Advertising" below, we may use third party analytics providers and technologies, including cookies and similar tools, to assist us in understanding how the Kiip Web Services are used.
  * **Cookies and other technologies.** When you use the Kiip Web Services, we use persistent and session cookies and other similar technologies to perform various tasks including to: (a) store your Dashboard account username and password; (b) analyze the usage of our Web Services; and (c) customize the Kiip Web Services to your preferences;. You can find more information about cookies and how to manage them at <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can modify your browser settings to decline cookies by visiting your browser's help page. If you choose to decline cookies, please note that you may not be able to sign in, customize, or use some features of the Kiip Web Services. By using the Kiip Web Services with your browser set to accept cookies you are consenting to our use of cookies in the manner described above.
  * **Web Beacons/Web Bugs:** In addition to cookies, we and/or our third-party advertising partners may use a technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs) that help us better manage and analyze content. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on web pages. Where permissible under applicable law, we may also include Web beacons in email messages or newsletters to determine whether the message has been opened and for other analytics purposes.
  * **Third Party Online Analytics and Tailored Advertising Online Analytics.** To help us better understand your use of the Kiip Web Services, we may use third-party web analytics providers, such as Google Analytics. These service providers use the sort of technology described in the "Cookies and Other Technologies" Section above. The information collected by this technology will be disclosed to or collected directly by these service providers, who use the information to evaluate users’ use of the websites. To prevent Google Analytics from collecting or using your information, you may install the Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-on.

**7\. How We Use the Information We Collect via the Kiip Web Services**

  * We use the information we collect from and about you through the Kiip Web Services to:
  * Provide the Kiip Web Services
  * Manage your Publisher account
  * Communicate with you, including responding to your inquiries, informing you about products and services, and notifying you of new features
  * Fulfill your requests for products and services and conduct business with you (e.g. reporting and payment)
  * Generate reports about our user base and service usage patterns, analyze the accuracy, effectiveness, and popularity of the service
  * Kiip retains the collected information for so long as we continue to provide the Kiip Services.

**8\. How We Share the Information We Collect via the Kiip Web Services**

We will share the information we collect through the Kiip Web Services only in the ways that are described in this Privacy Policy. We may share your information in the following ways:

  * **Service Providers.** We may share your information with a variety of service providers who perform services on our behalf. Unless we tell you otherwise, service providers are only permitted to use your information on our behalf and cannot use it for their own purposes. These service providers include analytics providers, advertisers, payment processors, product fulfillment providers, providers of technical infrastructure, engineers or other technical support, email providers, and customer support vendors.
  * **Legal Purposes.** We may share your information when we believe in good faith that such sharing is reasonably necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding possible illegal activities or to comply with legal process to the extent permissible by applicable laws. We may also share your information in situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of this Privacy Policy or the Terms of Service; or to respond to the claims of violation of the rights of third parties and/or to protect the rights, property and safety of Kiip, our employees, users, or the public and obtaining your consent is difficult. This may involve the sharing of your information with law enforcement, government agencies, courts, and/or other organizations.
  * **Business Transaction.** We may share your information in connection with any merger, reorganization, a sale of some or all Kiip assets, or a financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company.
  * **Consent.** We may share your information in any other circumstances where we have your consent.

**9\. Kiip Cross Device Practices**

Data collected from a particular browser or device may be used with another computer or device that is linked to the browser or device on which such data was collected, or transferred to a non-Affiliate for such purposes.

Data collected and used for cross device linking may include any or all of the Kiip Ad Platform and Kiip Web Services data points described in the sections above.

When you submit your Device ID through Kiip’s Opt-Out tool, Kiip will no longer use data collected from that Device for use in IBA, on that Device or any linked Device. Further, Kiip will not use the data collected from any linked Device for use in IBA on the Device that has been opted-out. Please note, however, that opting-out for a particular Device does not opt you out from IBA on all other linked devices, and you must complete the opt out process for each Device separately.

**10\. Kiip General Privacy Practices**

  * **How We Secure Your Information:** We have put in place physical, electronic, and managerial procedures designed to safeguard, and to help prevent unauthorized access to your information and to maintain data security. These safeguards take into account the sensitivity of the information that we collect, process and store and the current state of technology. Although we take appropriate measures to safeguard against unauthorized disclosures of information, the Internet and the services are not 100% secure so we cannot assure you that information we collect or store will be protected from all unauthorized access.
  * **International Users (outside of the EU):** If you are located outside the United States in a country other than one European Union and choose to use our services, engage with ads served by Kiip, and/or provide information to us, your information is provided to Kiip in the United States, and may be and processed and stored in the United States and otherwise outside of your country of residence, by Kiip and by third parties with whom we share in accordance with this Privacy Policy. By using the services, you consent to the export of your information outside of your country of residence.
  * **Children:** Kiip does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from children under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly allow such persons to use our services. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to engage with the Kiip Ad Platform or with Kiip Web Services or send any information about yourself to us. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verified parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [privacy@kiip.me](mailto:privacy@kiip.me).
  * **Changes to Our Privacy Policy:** We reserve the right to amend this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect changes in the law, our data collection and use practices, the features of our services, or advances in technology. Please check this page periodically for changes. Use of information we collect is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information was first collected. Please review the changes carefully. Your continued use of our services following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy will mean you consent to and accept those changes.
  * **Links to Third Party Sites and Services:** Our services may contain links to third-party websites, including social media services. Your use of these features may result in the collection, processing or sharing of information about you, depending on the feature. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of other websites or services that may be linked on our services. We do not endorse or make any representations about third-party websites or services. The information you choose to provide to or that is collected by these third parties is not covered by our Privacy Policy. We strongly encourage you to read such third parties' privacy policies.
  * **Notice to California Users:** California law permits users who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, a list of the third parties to whom we have disclosed their personal information (if any) for their direct marketing purposes in the prior calendar year, as well as the type of personal information disclosed to those parties.
  * **Accessing and Deleting Your Information:** You may, under applicable law, have the right to access, correct, update or delete the personal information Kiip holds about you. In order to exercise your rights, to the extent permitted and required of Kiip under applicable law, please contact us at [privacy@kiip.me](mailto:privacy@kiip.me). If you have a Kiip Dashboard account, you may, through your account settings, access and, in some cases, change or delete your username and password, email address, and user profile information that you have previously entered. The information you can view and update through your account settings may change as the Kiip Web Services change. You may also request to access or remove personal information we have about you by emailing us at [privacy@kiip.me](mailto:privacy@kiip.me). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

### CUSTOMER SUPPORT

If while using one of our Partner Apps you recognize a problem with an integrated Kiip ad and notify us of the problem or otherwise contact us via email or with a question, we will ask for your email address or other contact information so that you can receive a response. We will only use your email address for the purposes of communicating with you to resolve the issue.

If you have any questions or concerns regarding our privacy policies, please send us a message to [privacy@kiip.me](mailto:privacy@kiip.me) or mail us at Kiip, Inc., 970 Folsom Street, San Francisco, CA 94107, U.S., Attn: Privacy.

**11\. Opting Out of the Kiip Ad Platform**

As described above, we use the information we collect when you use our Partner Apps or visit our website for purposes including, but not limited to, serving you with interest-based ads, offers, and rewards based on your inferred interests, preferences and location.

If you prefer not to receive ads, offers, or rewards that are tailored to your interests (Interest-based Advertising or IBA), you can opt out of Kiip in two ways:

  1. When you receive an email from Kiip, you may opt out of receiving further emails by clicking on the 'unsubscribe' link in the footer of the email you received. This link will take you to a webpage where the only action that is required is to click 'Unsubscribe.'
  2. To opt out of Kiip Interest-based Advertising (IBA), click or tap the 'Begin Opt Out' link below. Your Mobile Advertising ID will be automatically transferred to the Kiip Opt-Out page. All you need to do from there is click or tap submit. If your Mobile Advertising ID does not transfer or if you are entering it manually, you can find instructions below and on our Opt-Out page to help you identify it.

When you choose to Opt-out through the Kiip Opt-Out page, Kiip will no longer use data collected from that Device for use in Interest-based Advertising (IBA), on that Device or any linked Device. Further, Kiip will not use the data collected from any linked Device for use in IBA on the Device that has been opted-out.

Please note, however, that opting-out for a particular Device does not opt you out from IBA on all other linked devices, and you must complete the opt out process for each Device separately.

As an alternative to using the Kiip opt-out tool, you can also opt out of Kiip's IBA by changing your device's IBA opt-out setting. Instructions for doing so can be found at <https://www.networkadvertising.org/mobile-choice>.

In addition to using the above methods to opt out of Kiip IBA practices, you can opt out of other platforms by downloading the "AppChoices" mobile application from your App Store or via the Digital Advertising Alliance App Choices page at <http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices>.

Finding your Advertiser ID:

_For iOS Devices, including iPhone, iPad, and iPod touch:_

At present, the advertising ID on iOS devices is hidden from users by Apple by default but can be retrieved with third-party apps. Apple calls this identifier an "Identifier for Advertisers" or IDFA. An Apple IDFA is somewhat analogous to an advertising cookie, and enables advertisers to understand that a user of a particular phone has taken an action like a click or an app install.

In order to find your Apple IDFA, a third party tool is required. There is a wide selection of apps with the capability on the App Store. Below are a selection of apps for iOS that can show a device's IDFA to users.

_For Android:_

To find your Android Advertising Identifier, open the Google Settings app on your Android device and click on "Ads." Your Advertising Identifier will be listed at the bottom of the screen.

Kiip, Inc.  
Effective Date: May 30, 2018
